Guide to the William S. Downing papers, 1922-2006.
Downing, William S. papers,
- Series V. Drawings
  - Malott Hall Renovations Final Schematic Phas, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 1997; 413
    Project # 97-738
  - Malott Hall Renovations Part 1, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 1998; 413
  - Malott Hall Renovations Part 2, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 1998; 414
  - Malott Hall, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 1975; 415
    Project # 7411
  - Malott Hall, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 1985; 415
    Project # 88332
  - Cornell Golf Center, Cornell University, Town of Ithaca, New York, 416
  - Canine Research, 1998; 417
    Project # 98-751
  - CCC-Tech Rooms, 1998; 418
    Project # 98-756
  - Grand Residence, Erin, New York, 1999; 419
  - Grand Residence, Erin, New York, 1999; 420
  - Computing and Communications Center (C.C.C.), Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 1998; 421
  - Computing and Communications Center (C.C.C.), Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 1998; 421
    Project # 98-763
  - Computing and Communications Center (C.C.C.), Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 1998; 422
  - Hollister Hall, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 423
  - Hollister Hall, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 424
  - Physicians Office Building II, Oneida, New York, 2000; 425
  - Cooley Professional Building, Oneida, New York, 426
  - Cooley Medical Building,, Oneida, New York - Thomas R. Pruckno AIA, Dupler Segna, Inc. Architects, 1993; 427
    Project # 92528
  - Physicians Office Building II, Oneida, New York, 2000; 428
  - La Tourelle Country Inn, Ithaca, New York, 1983; 429
    Project # 1983-568
  - La Tourelle Country Inn, Ithaca, New York, 1983; 430
  - La Tourelle Country Inn, Ithaca, New York, 1983; 431
  - La Tourelle Country Inn, Ithaca, New York, 1983; 432
  - La Tourelle Country Inn, Ithaca, New York, 1983; 433
  - La Tourelle Country Inn, Ithaca, New York, 2004; 434
    Project # 04-825
  - La Tourelle Country Inn - Spa Addition, Ithaca, New York, 2004; 435
  - La Tourelle Country Inn - Spa Addition, Ithaca, New York, 2004; 436
  - Unitarian Church Annex Project, 2000; 437
    Project # 00-801
  - Monarch Machine Tool Company Expansion, 1991; 438
  - Paolangy Residence, 439
  - Crescent Beach Salisbury Residence, Jerusalem, New York, 440
  - King Residence, 441
  - Schoellkopf Memorial Hall Studies, 2000; 442
    Project # 00-789
  - Schoellkopf Memorial Hall, Copies of Original Drawings - Gibb and Waltz, Architects, 1913; 442
    Project # 1307
  - Day Treatment Facility, J.N. Adam Developmental Center, 1986; 443
  - Tompkins County Mental Health Services Building, 1988; 444
  - Glen National Bank - Drive-In Office, Watkins Glen, New York, 1962; 445
    Project # 338
  - Glen National Bank - Addition to Drive-In, Watkins Glen, New York, 1962; 445
  - Frankel Residence, Charlottesville, Virginia - Edward D. Stone, Architect, Drawn or Checked by W. Downing, 1952; 446
    Project # 128
  - House for Life Magazine - Edward D. Stone, Architect, Drawn or Checked by W. Downing, 1957; 446
    Project # 190
  - Kimmel Residence, Mamaroneck, New York - Edward D. Stone, Architect, Drawn or Checked by W. Downing, 1958; 446
    Project # 184
  - Embassy of the U.S.A., New Delhi, India - Edward D. Stone, Drawn or Checked by W. Downing, 1956; 447
  - Martha Van Rensselaer Hall, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 1999; 448
  - Multipurpose Field House, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 448
  - Ag Quad Planning Study, 448
  - Uris Library, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 2001; 448
  - Physical Science Building, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 2001; 448
  - Olin Library Proposed Scheme; Millwork, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 448
  - Overlook Park aka Cliffside, Ithaca, New York, 1988; 449
    Project # 88-625
  - Jefferson Apartments, Trumansburg, NY, 1992; 450
  - Taughannock - Administration Building, 1960; 451
    Project # 60-289
  - 319 College Ave., 1984; 452
  - Belmont Baptist Church, Charlottesville, Virginia, 1953; 453
  - Delaware County Park, 1967; 454
  - Harborside Village, 1982; 454
    Project # 553
  - Hospicare, 1991; 454
    Project # 669
  - Schurman Hall Entrance Study, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 1999; 455
    Project # 99-767
  - Schurman Hall Miscellaneous, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 455
  - Cornell Visitors Center Study, Balch and Noyes Halls, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 1999; 455
  - Duffield Hall, Cornell University, College of Engineering, Ithaca, New York, 455
  - University Cooperative Nursery, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 1997; 455
    Project # 97-730
  - University Cooperative Nursery, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 1998; 455
    Project # 98-745
  - Acrographics Inc.- J. Victor Bagnardi, Architect formerly N.Y. Telephone Office Co. - Richard E. Metzger, Architect, Ithaca, New York, 1976; 456
  - Cortland County Court House, Cortland, New York - J.Riely Gordon, Architect, 457
  - Ithaca Senior High School, Ithaca, New York - Perkins & Will, Architects, 1958; 458
  - Ithaca Senior High School, Ithaca, New York - Perkins & Will, Architects, 1958; 459
  - Ithaca Senior High School, Ithaca, New York - Perkins & Will, Architects, 1958; 460
  - Ithaca Senior High School - Part 1, Ithaca, New York - Perkins & Will, Architects, 1958; 461
  - Ithaca Senior High School, Part 2, Ithaca, New York - Perkins & Will, Architects, 1958; 462
  - Ithaca Savings Bank, Ithaca, New York - Gibb & Waltz, Architects, 1922; 463
  - Unidentified drawings, 1923; 463
  - Tompkins County Public Library, Ithaca, New York - J. Victor Bagnardi, Architect, 1965; 464
    Project # 65-20
  - Ithaca Downtown: Diazo Prints, Aerial Photos; Working Drawing Plans of City Car Park Behind Izards, 1987; 465
  - Ithaca State Street Mall, "The Commons," Ithaca, New York - Anton J. Egner and Assc., Architects, 465
  - Greenport Jazz Park, 1996; 466
  - Druyan Residence, Ithaca, New York, 2000; 467
    Project # 98-760
  - Sagan Residence, Village of Cayuga Heights, New York - Levatich, Miller, Hoffman, Architects, 1974; 467
    Project # 7218
  - Stahl Residence, 468
  - 214 Eddy Street, Ithaca, New York, 468
  - Ithaca City Hall, Renovation, Ithaca, New York, 1998; 469
  - Office Building for Lynwood-Slater Corp at 108 Green St. (now City Hall), Ithaca, New York - Carl Cornwell Tallman, Architect, 1931; 469
  - Barnes Hall, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 1999; 470
    Project # 99-781
  - Wilson Laboratory, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 2001; 471
  - Wilson Synchrotron Colliding Beam Facility, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 1975; 471
    Project # 2085
  - Wilson Synchrotron Colliding Beam Facility, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 1977; 471
  - Wilson Synchrotron Colliding Beam Facility, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 1984; 471
  - G-Line Study, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 1998; 471
    Project # 98-737
  - Chess Addition Study, 471
  - Goldwin Smith Hall, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York - Holt, Architects, 1995; 472
    Project # 94055
  - Goldwin Smith Hall, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York - Holt, Architects, 1995; 472
    Project # 9513
  - Uris Hall, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 1995; 472
  - 704 Five Mile Drive, 1996; 473
  - Liberman Residence, 1990; 473
  - Specifications for Residence #122, 473
  - Executive Lodge, 1981; 473
    Project # 81-529
  - World War II Memorial, 473
  - W.C.T.A. Federal Credit Union, Land Survey, Sodus, New York - RSA Architects, 1998; 473
    Project # 98-896
  - Denver Bronco's Corporate Offices & Training Center, Scottsbluff Sash and Door Co., Denver, Colorado, 1989; 473
  - Warehouse/Office, Lyons, New York - Stephen Holdridge, Architect, 1991; 473
  - Undergraduate Office of Admissions, East Hill Plaza Renovatins, Cornell University ,Ithaca, New York, 2000; 474
    Project # 85714
  - 410 Thurston/Admissions, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 1980; 474
  - Malott Hall, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 475
  - Hangar Theater, Ithaca, New York, 476
  - Tompkins County Jail and Court House - Fred H. Thomas, Architect, 1992; 477
  - Schoellkopf Memorial Hall, 2000; 478
  - Freeville Community Residence, 1994; 479
  - East Hill High School Condominiums, 1997; 479
  - Cortland Best Car Wash Addition, 1996; 479
    Project # 96-713
  - Vineyard Residence, Ithaca, New York, 1996; 479
  - J. Michael's Restaurant, Ithaca, New York, 1996; 479
  - Newlin Residence, Brooktondale, New York, 1996; 479
  - 411 North Tioga Street, Ithaca, New York, 1996; 479
  - Halkiopoulos, Ithaca, New York, 1997; 479
  - Gardner Residence, Ithaca, New York, 1999; 480
    Project # 99--765
  - Old Hundred, Ithaca, New York, 1996; 480
  - Downtown Ithaca Schemes, Ithaca, New York, 480
  - Odyssey Research Associate Inc. Ascot Place, Lansing, New York, 480
  - Hollister Hall, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 481
  - Visitor Center at Balch and Noyes Hall - Study, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 1999; 481
  - Uris Library, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 2000; 481
  - Junior High, 1930; 482
    Project # 3002
  - Cayuga Preventorium, 1937; 482
    Project # 176
  - Wilcox Residence - Holt, Architect, 1938; 482
    Project # 23
  - Alt. to Newman House - Holt, Architect, 1941; 482
  - 121 E. Buffalo Office Exp. & Design, Ithaca, New York, 1967; 482
    Project # 421
  - Professor & Mrs. Robert W. Langhans, 482
    Project # 332
  - Cunningham Residence - Holt, Architect, 1939; 483
    Project # 36
  - Kiewiet Residence - Holt, Architect, 1941; 483
    Project # 67
  - C.L. Parsons Residence - Holt, Architect, 1945; 483
  - Bogena Residence Alt. - Holt, Architect, 1945; 483
  - Masterman Residence - Holt, Architect, 1946; 483
  - Avery Residence - Gibb & Holt, Architects, 1948; 483
  - Wallace Scrap Iron & Metal - Holt & Conley, Architects, 1949; 483
  - Barrett Residence, Virginia, 1952; 483
  - Crouch Residence - Hill, Architect, 485
  - Ithaca Central School, Ithaca, New York - Gibb & Waltz, Architect, 1923; 485
  - Masonic Temple - Gibb & Waltz, Architects, 1925; 485
  - St. Luke's Church Detail - Drawn by John Tilton, 1953; 485
  - Ithaca Central School, Ithaca, New York - Holt, Architect, 1959; 485
    Project # 299
  - Cayuga Heights Elementary, Cayuga Heights, New York - Holt, Architect, 1959; 485
  - Lawrence Residence - Holt, Architect, 1956; 485
  - Kitchen for Penny's - Holt & Downing, Architects, 1961; 485
  - Salvatore Indelicato, Jr. Apartments, 486
  - First Methodist Church of Dryden, Dryden, New York, 486
  - E.H.R. Hart, 486
    Project # 316
  - Nichols Elementary School Addition, 486
    Project # 318
  - Finger Lakes Automobile Club, 486
  - A.H. Treman Swimming Pool, 486
    Project # 328
  - Administration Building Finger Lakes State Park Commission - Holt & Downing, Architects, 1960; 487
    Project # 289
  - Alpha Omicron Pi - Holt & Downing, 1961; 487
  - Ho. Mo. Co. Alteration, 1962; 487
  - Tioga Central School Addition, 487
    Project # 321
  - Addition to Office Building for Tompkins Coop Fire Insurance Co. - Holt, Architect, 487
    Project # 267
  - West Hill Park - Holt & Downing, Architects, 1964-1965; 488
  - East Hill School Sprinkler System, Ithaca, New York - Personios,Wadsworth,Molter Construction Engineering, 1969; 488
  - Cortland Urban Renewal, Cortland, New York, 1973; 488
  - Corning Prelim., 488
  - Residence for John P. Young Esq., Ithaca, New York, 488
  - Addition to Treman Cottage - Holt & Downing, Architects, 1961; 488
  - Ithaca Laundries - Petrillose Cleaners, Ithaca, New York, 489
  - U.S. Post Office Addition, Ithaca, New York, 489
  - Stagg - Addition, 489
    Project # 344
  - Ithaca Laundries - Petrillose Cleaners, Ithaca, New York, 490
  - W.C. Geer Apartments, 490
    Project # 339
  - George's Restaurant, 490
    Project # 343
  - Glen Motor Court, Franzese, 491
  - Dr. Lehmer, 491
    Project # 341
  - D.E. Ordway - Addition to Residence, 491
    Project # 346
  - Dr. Hazel J. Trefts Residence, Punsit Road, Spencertown, New York, 1963; 491
  - Mr. and Mrs. George Trefts, Aurora, New York, 1941; 491
    No project number listed.
  - Marathon Bus Garage, Marathon, New York, 492
  - Brockway Motors - Holt & Downing, Architects, 1960; 492
    Project # 296
  - Brockway Motors - Holt & Downing, Architects, 1960; 492
    Project # 309
  - Brockway Motors - Holt & Downing, Architects, 1960; 492
  - Dale Residence - Holt & Downing, Architects, 1959; 492
    Project # 306
  - Cortland Memorial Hospital, Cortland, New York - Holt, Architect, 1955; 492
    Project # 251
  - Crawford - Holt & Downing, Architects, 493
    Project # 304
  - Brockway Motors - Holt & Downing, Architects, 1960; 493
  - Brockway Motors - Holt & Downing, Architects, 1960; 493
  - Brockway Motors - Holt & Downing, Architects, 1960; 493
  - Tioga School, 493
  - Tioga School, 493
  - USPO, 493
  - Brockway Motors - Holt & Downing, 494
  - Brockway Motors - Holt & Downing, Architects, 1960; 494
  - Brockway Motors - Holt & Downing, Architects, 1960; 494
  - Tioga School, 494
  - Tioga School, 494
  - U.S. Post Office Misc. Base Drawings, Ithaca, New York, 494
  - Tioga School, 495
  - Tioga School, 495
  - Ithaca Jr. High School, Ithaca, New York - Holt, Architect, 1956; 495
  - Tioga School, 496
  - Tioga School, 496
  - Uan Riper - Holt, Architect, 1959; 496
    Project # 297
  - Woodstock Apartments - Holt & Downing, Architects, 496
    Project # 300
  - Tioga School, 497
  - Tioga School, 497
  - ZBT Fraternity, Ithaca, New York - Buchman & Kahn, Architects, 1923; 497
  - Paleontology Research - Holt, Architect, 1959; 497
    Project # 290
  - Stevens - Holt, Architect, 1956; 497
    Project # 269
  - Co-Op Dining - Holt, Architect, 1953; 498
    Project # 234
  - Benson - Holt, Architect, 1941; 498
    Project # 52
  - Finch, 1959; 498
    Project # 301
  - Central School, Ithaca, New York - Gibb & Walz, Architects, 1922; 498
    Project # 2213
  - Addition to Offices for George B. Bailey Ins., 498
    Project # 449
  - Elks Club, Ithaca, New York - Gibb & Walz, Architects, 1916; 498
  - Elks Club, Ithaca, New York - Gibb & Walz, Architects, 1916; 499
  - Ludloville School, Lansing, New York - Gibb, Architect, 1929; 499
  - Rural Radio Network Studio, Savings Bank Building, Ithaca, New York, 1948; 499
    Project # 166
  - Rural Radio Network Studio, Savings Bank Building, Ithaca, New York, 1948; 499
    Project # 167
  - Roy H. Park Addition - Larkin, Architect, 1951; 499
    Project # 278
  - Roy H. Park Addition - Holt, Architect, 1958; 499
  - Lent - Holt, 1958; 499
    Project # 287
  - GLF Offices South Hill Terrace, Ithaca, New York - Gibb, Architect, 1935; 500
    Project # 3502
  - Clute Residence - Holt & Gibb, Architects, 1948; 500
    Project # 164
  - C.E. Treman Beach House and Pool, 500
  - Geer Lab - Holt, Architect, 1956; 501
    Project # 263
  - Nichols Elementary School - Holt, Architect, 1957; 501
  - Reconstruction Home, 501
  - Penn Yan Launching Site, New York State Conservation Comm., 501
    Project # 414
  - Hurd - Holt, Architect, 1955; 502
    Project # 260
  - Orcultt Motel - Holt, Architect, 1958; 502
    Project # 288
  - Finger Lakes State Park Comm. Administration Building, 1960; 502
  - Townley Motors - Holt, Architect, 1954; 503
    Project # 236
  - Belle Sherman - Holt, Architect, 1955; 503
  - Lewis Hooker - Holt, Architect, 1954; 503
    Project # 255
  - Baptist Church - Holt, Architect, 1957; 504
    Project # 270
  - Larken - Holt, Architect, 1956; 504
    Project # 271
  - Bartow - Holt, Architect, 1958; 504
    Project # 282
  - Lutz - Holt, Architect, 1959; 504
    Project # 292
  - Flight - Holt, Architect, 1958; 505
    Project # 284
  - Owego Baptist Church, Owego, New York - Holt, Architect, 1959; 505
  - Finger Lakes State Park Comm. Administration Building, 1960; 505
  - Barcelona Harbor Comm. - Revitalized, 505
    Project # 438
  - Sienko, 505
    Project # 380
  - Finger Lakes State Park Comm. Administration Building, 1960; 506
  - Boyton Jr. High - Gibb, Architect, 1930; 507
  - Boyton Jr. High - Holt, Architect, 1957; 507
  - Holcomb Residence - Addition, 507
  - Skaneatles State Marina Park Feasibility Study, 507
    Project # 441
  - Chenango Valley State Park Changes & Additions to Golf Facility, 507
  - Residence for Mrs. William B. Kerr, 508
  - Watkins Salt Co., 508
  - McGraw Housing, 1966-1967; 508
    Project # 389-5
  - Mud Lock, New York State Conservation Comm., 509
    Project # 416
  - Hamann Residence Renovation, 509
    Project # 430
  - Serling Residence, 509
  - Addition to Offices for George B. Bailey Ins., 1939; 509
  - Dr. E.C. King, 509
    Project # 285
  - Clinic for Dr. Palmer & Mills, 509
    Project # 355
  - Abbott Residence, 510
  - Alpha Chi Sigma Fraternity, 510
    Project # 399
  - Westview Terrace, 510
    Project # 400
  - Wiliam Tucker Dean, 510
  - Warren W. Clute Memorial Park Skating Rink, Watkins Glen, New York, 511
  - St. John's Church - Kitchen Remodeling, 511
    Project # 412
  - Watkins Glen Launching Site, New York State Conservation Comm., Watkins Glen, New York, 511
    Project # 413
  - Penn Yan Launching Site, New York State Conservation Comm., 511
  - Otisco, New York State Conservation Comm., 512
  - Delaware County Park, 512
  - Watkins Salt Company Addition, 512
    Project # 423
  - Wilcox Cottage - Holt & Gibb, Architects, 1949; 512
    Project # 196
  - Erdman Residence - Additions, 513
  - R.A. Heggie Brothers - Remodeling, 1965; 513
  - Phi Gamma Delta Addition, 513
  - Waaland Residence, 514
  - St. Paul's Addition, 514
  - Clynes Residence, 515
  - Curtiss - Holt, Architect, 515
  - Dr. Hall, 516
    Project # 360
  - Office of Dr. Edward C. Hall - Alteration, 516
  - Dr. & Mrs. Leo Speno - Alteration, 516
    Project # 357
  - Dr. E.C.King Residence - Alteration, Ithaca, New York, 516
  - Lehigh Valley House, 1950; 516
  - Purity, 517
    Project # 352
  - McGraw, 1966; 517
    Project # 389
  - Newark Valley Central School, 1966; 517
  - Phi Gamma Delta Addition, 517
  - Prof. Van Tucker Dean Addition - Holt, Architect, 1953; 518
  - School & Parish For Trinity Church, Ashland, Oregon - Holt, Architect, 1954; 518
  - Leon Rothchild Apartment Addition - Holt, Architect, 1943; 518
  - Repairs to Congregational Church, Ithaca, New York - Holt & Gibb, Architects, 1949; 518
    Project # 175
  - Hartman Residence Rt. 34B, Ithaca, New York - Holt, Architect, 1959; 518
  - Gas Station Vacuum Oil Co., 1937; 518
  - Primary School Mill & Albany - Gibb & Waltz, Architects, 1922; 519
  - Corners Comm. Center, Cayuga Heights, New York, Holt & Gibb, Architects, 1947-1948; 519
  - Airport Terminal For Robinson Airlines - Holt, Architect, 1947; 519
  - Residence for F.C. Cornell - Gibb, Architect, 1927; 519
    Project # 2701
  - Cayuga Preventorium, Ithaca, New York - Holt & Larkin, Architects, 1936; 520
  - Residence for Mrs George Hull - Holt, Architect, 1958; 520
  - Addition to Garage for P.T. Egbert - Holt, Architect, 1958; 520
  - Tompkin County Hospital Chapel - Holt, Architect, 1959; 521
  - Sigma Phi Epsilon Fraternity - Holt, Architect, 521
  - J.G. Prichard Garage Addition - Holt, Architect, 1951; 521
    Project # 221
  - W.C. Geer Addition - Holt, Architect, 1959; 521
  - Anderson - Holt, Architect, 1941; 521
    Project # 58
  - Guantlett Alteration - Holt, Architect, 1951; 521
  - Hirshfield Residence - Holt, Architect, 1947; 522
    Project # 156
  - Matthewson - Holt & Gibb, Architects, 1947; 522
    Project # 165
  - Butterworth - Holt, Architect, 1941; 522
    Project # 170
  - Knights of Columbus - Holt & Gibb, Architects, 1947; 522
    Project # 174
  - Morris Lewis - Holt & Gibb, Architects, 1948; 522
    Project # 179
  - MacDonald - Holt & Gibb, Architects, 1949; 523
  - Dr. Speno - Holt & Gibb, Architects, 1949; 523
  - Eberle Residence - Holt, Architect, 1956; 523
  - Clynes Moore - Holt, Architect, 1950; 523
    Project # 210
  - West Hill School Addition, Ithaca, New York - Holt, Architect, 1951; 524
    Project # 192-A
  - Votilla - Holt & Gibb, Architects, 1950; 524
    Project # 200
  - Dusinberre - Holt, Architect, 1941; 525
  - Durland - Holt & Gibb, Architects, 1949; 525
    Project # 201
  - St. John's Church - Holt, Architect, 1950; 525
    Project # 205
  - St. John's Church - Holt & Downing, Architects, 1960; 525
    Project # 256
  - Garage for Reconstruction Home - Holt, Architect, 1950; 525
    Project # 209
  - Moore - Drawings by D.R. King, 1937; 525
  - Spencer School - Holt, Architect, 1951; 526
  - Schuyler City Office Building - Holt, Architect, 1952; 526
  - Lyon Scout Building, 1951; 526
    Project # 217
  - Cornell Poultry Research Lab, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 526
    Project # 382